<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>diabetes on Matthew Snelson</title>
    <link>/tags/diabetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in diabetes on Matthew Snelson</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/diabetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Complement C5a Induces Renal Injury in Diabetic Kidney Disease Via Disruption in Mitochondrial Metabolic Agility</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_tan_diabetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_tan_diabetes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tan S, Ziemann M, Thallas-Bonke V, &lt;strong&gt;Snelson M&lt;/strong&gt;, Baker S, Jerums G, Skene A, Power D, MacIsaac R, Henstridge D, Wetsel R, Meikle P, El-Osta A, Forbes J, Cooper M, Ekinci E, Woodruff T, Coughlan M: Complement C5a Induces Renal Injury in Diabetic Kidney Disease Via Disruption in Mitochondrial Metabolic Agility &lt;em&gt;Diabetes&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 69, Issue 1, 2020, Pages 83-98&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diabetes and the gut microbiota: sorting through the crap</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-adc-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-adc-3/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;slides&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Slides:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pdf/2019_ADEA_microbiome.pdf&#34;&gt;My Presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;pdf/2019_ADEA_NK.pdf&#34;&gt;Dr Nicole Kellow’s Presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;abstract&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a recent explosion in research exploring the role of the microbiota in many disease states, including diabetes and metabolic disorders, fuelled by technological improvements and a reduction in the cost of microbiota sequencing. This session will provide an overview of the composition and function of the gut microbiota with particular relevance given to the role of the microbiota in diabetes and metabolic disorders. Key takeaways will include an understanding of how the microbiota is measured and the relative merits of different techniques, an appreciation of the common visualisations that are used to display the highly multidimensional data that are produced from microbiota sequencing, including the ability to interpret these findings, and an awareness of future directions of this field, in particular the relevance of microbiota testing to patient care within hospital and clinic settings. This symposium will also provide an overview of the lifestyle factors influencing the composition of the gut microbiota, including dietary prebiotics and probiotics, physical activity and sleep quality. Interventions used to favourably manipulate the composition of the gut microbiota in diabetes will be discussed, including interpretation of the evidence supporting the efficacy of these interventions. Following attendance at this symposium, participants will be able to provide practical and evidence-based advice about gut microbial measurement and manipulation to their patients with diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic effects of resistant starch type 2: a systematic literature review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_snelson_rs-slr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_snelson_rs-slr/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Snelson&lt;/strong&gt;, Jessica Jong, Deanna Manolas, Smonda Kok, Audrey Louise, Romi Stern, Nicole J Kellow, Metabolic effects of resistant starch type 2: a systematic literature review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials, &lt;em&gt;Nutrients&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 11, Issue 8, 2019, Page 1833&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic effects of resistant starch type 2: a systematic literature review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-nsa-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-nsa-2/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;abstract&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published evidence exploring effects of dietary resistant starch (RS) on cardiometabolic health is inconsistent. This review aimed to investigate the effect of dietary RS type 2 (RS2) supplementation on body weight, satiety ratings, fasting plasma glucose, HbA1c, insulin resistance and lipid levels in healthy individuals and those with overweight/obesity, the metabolic syndrome (MetS) or type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). Five electronic databases were searched for Randomised Controlled Trials (RCTs) published in English between 1982-2017, investigating the effect of dietary RS2 supplementation on cardiometabolic health.
Trials were eligible for inclusion if they reported RCTs involving humans where at least one group received ≥10 grams of RS2 per day for ≥1 week, and measured body weight, satiety, glucose and/or lipid metabolic outcomes. Twenty RCTs involving 569 participants were included. RS2 supplementation significantly reduced serum triacylglycerol concentrations (Mean difference= -0.11 mmol/L; 95% CI -0.18, -0.04, P=0.002) in healthy individuals (n=227) and reduced body weight (MD= -1.29kg; 95% CI -2.40, -0.17, P=0.02) in people with T2DM (n=90), but had no effect on appetite, fasting plasma glucose, HbA1c, HOMA-IR, total cholesterol, LDL-cholesterol or HDL-cholesterol in any patient sub-groups. Most studies had a moderate-high risk of bias, were of short duration and contained small sample sizes. High quality, long-term trials are required to determine the efficacy of RS2 supplementation as a dietary strategy in the management of metabolic disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
