<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>microbiota on Matthew Snelson</title>
    <link>/tags/microbiota/</link>
    <description>Recent content in microbiota on Matthew Snelson</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/microbiota/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Processed foods drive intestinal barrier permeability and microvascular diseases</title>
      <link>/publication/2021_snelson_sciadvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2021_snelson_sciadvs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Snelson&lt;/strong&gt;, Sih Min Tan, Rachel E. Clarke, Cassandra de Pasquale, Vicki Thallas-Bonke, Tuong-Vi Nguyen, Sally A. Penfold, Brooke E. Harcourt, Karly C. Sourris, Runa S. Lindblom, Mark Ziemann, David Steer, Assam El-Osta, Michael J. Davies, Leigh Donnellan, Permal Deo, Nicole J. Kellow, Mark E. Cooper, Trent M. Woodruff, Charles R. Mackay, Josephine M. Forbes, Melinda T. Coughlan: Processed foods drive intestinal barrier permeability and microvascular diseases, Science Advances. 7, 14, 15 p., eabe4841.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long term high protein diet feeding alters the microbiome and increases intestinal permeability, systemic inflammation and kidney injury in mice</title>
      <link>/publication/2021_snelson_hpd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2021_snelson_hpd/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Snelson&lt;/strong&gt;, Rachel Elise Clarke, Tuong-Vi Nguyen, Sally Anne Penfold, Josephine Maree Forbes, Sih Min Tan, Melinda Therese Coughlan, Long term high protein diet feeding alters the microbiome and increases intestinal permeability, systemic inflammation and kidney injury in mice, Molecular Nutrition and Food Research 2021, 2000851&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut microbiome, prebiotics, intestinal permeability and diabetes complications</title>
      <link>/publication/2021_snelson_beem-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2021_snelson_beem-review/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Snelson&lt;/strong&gt;, Cassandra de Pasquale, Elif I. Ekinci, Melinda T. Coughlan, Gut microbiome, prebiotics, intestinal permeability and diabetes complications, Best Practice &amp;amp; Research Clinical Endocrinology &amp;amp; Metabolism 2021, 101507&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deficiency of Prebiotic Fibre and Insufficient Signalling Through Gut Metabolite Sensing Receptors Leads to Cardiovascular Disease</title>
      <link>/publication/2020_kaye_circ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2020_kaye_circ/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David M Kaye, Waled Shihata, Hamdi A Jama, Kirill Tsyganov, Mark Ziemann, Helen Kiriazis, Duncan Horlock, Amrita Vijay, Beverly Giam, Antony Vinh, Chad Johnson, April Fiedler, Daniel Donner, &lt;strong&gt;Matthew Snelson&lt;/strong&gt;, Melinda T Coughlan, Sarah Phillips, Xiao-Jun Du, Assam El-Osta, Grant Drummond, Gavin W Lambert, Tim Spector, Ana M Valdes, Charles R Mackay, Francine Z Marques, Deficiency of Prebiotic Fibre and Insufficient Signalling Through Gut Metabolite Sensing Receptors Leads to Cardiovascular Disease, &lt;em&gt;Circulation&lt;/em&gt;, 2020 (epub ahead of print)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Renal Clinician&#39;s Guide to the Gut Microbiota</title>
      <link>/publication/2020_snelson_microbiota-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2020_snelson_microbiota-guide/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Snelson&lt;/strong&gt;, Annabel Biruete, Catherine McFarlane, Katrina Campbell, A Renal Clinician&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Gut Microbiota, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Renal Nutrition&lt;/em&gt;, 2020 (epub ahead of print)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
