<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>complement activation on Matthew Snelson</title>
    <link>/tags/complement-activation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in complement activation on Matthew Snelson</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/complement-activation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Complement C5a Induces Renal Injury in Diabetic Kidney Disease Via Disruption in Mitochondrial Metabolic Agility</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_tan_diabetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_tan_diabetes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tan S, Ziemann M, Thallas-Bonke V, &lt;strong&gt;Snelson M&lt;/strong&gt;, Baker S, Jerums G, Skene A, Power D, MacIsaac R, Henstridge D, Wetsel R, Meikle P, El-Osta A, Forbes J, Cooper M, Ekinci E, Woodruff T, Coughlan M: Complement C5a Induces Renal Injury in Diabetic Kidney Disease Via Disruption in Mitochondrial Metabolic Agility &lt;em&gt;Diabetes&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 69, Issue 1, 2020, Pages 83-98&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resistant starch is protective against diabetic nephropathy by inhibition of complement activation in a mouse model of diabetes</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-nsa-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-nsa-1/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;abstract&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complement activation occurs in diabetic nephropathy with the downstream complement component C5a activating the innate immune system, contributing to inflammation. Resistant starch (RS) may be nephro-protective however the effects of RS on complement activation and the innate immune system have not been explored. Six week old non-diabetic mice (dbh), diabetic mice (dbdb) and dbdb mice on a regular chow diet supplemented with 25% RS (dbdbRS) were maintained for ten weeks. 24-hour urine was collected for albumin and C5a measurement by ELISA. Kidneys were digested and enriched for leukocytes using Percoll gradient and flow cytometry was performed. Diabetes was associated with an increase in albuminuria (28.0±6.5 vs 411.3±275.8µg/24h, P&amp;lt;0.001, dbh vs dbdb), which was reduced in diabetic mice receiving RS supplementation (411.3±275.8 vs 125.6±37.3µg/24h, P&amp;lt;0.01, dbdb vs dbdbRS). Urinary C5a excretion was increased by diabetes (92.6±17.6 vs 1324.0±429.7pg/24h, P&amp;lt;0.001, dbh vs dbdb) and decreased by RS (1324.0±429.7 vs 577.7±123.1pg/24h, P&amp;lt;0.05, dbdb vs dbdbRS) and infiltrating renal macrophages were more likely to be positive for C5aR with diabetes (4.8±3.9 vs 54.0±27.8%, P&amp;lt;0.001, dbh vs dbdb), which RS supplementation reduced (54.0±27.8 vs 11.7±4.2%, P&amp;lt;0.01, dbdb vs dbdbRS). These studies support the notion that RS is protective against renal disease via inhibition of complement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dietary Resistant Starch Protects Against Diabetic Nephropathy by Inhibition of Complement</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-anzsn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-anzsn/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;abstract&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aim
To investigate immune mechanisms by which resistant starch (RS) supplementation may be protective against diabetic nephropathy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background
Activation of complement occurs in diabetic nephropathy. C5a is a downstream complement component that activates the innate immune system contributing to inflammation. Dietary RS may be nephro-protective, however the effects of dietary RS on complement activation and the innate immune system have not been explored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods
Six week old non-diabetic mice (db/h), diabetic mice (db/db) and db/db mice on a regular chow diet supplemented with 25% RS (dbdb+RS) were maintained for ten weeks. 24-hour urine was collected for albumin and C5a measurement by ELISA. Kidneys were digested and enriched for leukocytes using Percoll gradient. Cells were stained with BV786-CD45, AF700-CD11b, PE-Cy7-CD11c, BV711-Siglec F, BV605-Ly6C, PE-CD86, FITC-C5aR antibodies and flow cytometry was performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results
Diabetes was associated with an increase in albuminuria (28.0±6.5 vs 411.3±275.8µg/24h, P&amp;lt;0.001, dbh vs dbdb), which was reduced in diabetic mice receiving RS supplementation (411.3±275.8 vs 125.6±37.3µg/24h, P&amp;lt;0.01, dbdb vs dbdb+RS). Urinary C5a excretion was increased by diabetes (92.6±17.6 vs 1324.0±429.7pg/24h, P&amp;lt;0.001, dbh vs dbdb) and decreased by RS (1324.0±429.7 vs 577.7±123.1pg/24h, P&amp;lt;0.05, dbdb vs dbdb+RS). In diabetes there was an increase in CD86 MFI (a marker of activation) on infiltrating macrophages (CD45+ CD11b+ CD11c- Siglec F- Ly6C hi), which was attenuated with RS (3.7±1.8 vs 1.5±1.0 fold change to dbh, P&amp;lt;0.05, dbdb vs dbdb+RS). Furthermore, infiltrating macrophages were more likely to be positive for C5aR with diabetes (4.8±3.9 vs 54.0±27.8%, P&amp;lt;0.001, dbh vs dbdb), which RS supplementation reduced (54.0±27.8 vs 11.7±4.2%, P&amp;lt;0.01, dbdb vs dbdb+RS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions
These studies support the notion that dietary RS is protective against renal disease via inhibition of complement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
