<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Josephine M. Forbes on Matthew Snelson</title>
    <link>/authors/josephine-m.-forbes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Josephine M. Forbes on Matthew Snelson</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/authors/josephine-m.-forbes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Processed foods drive intestinal barrier permeability and microvascular diseases</title>
      <link>/publication/2021_snelson_sciadvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2021_snelson_sciadvs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Snelson&lt;/strong&gt;, Sih Min Tan, Rachel E. Clarke, Cassandra de Pasquale, Vicki Thallas-Bonke, Tuong-Vi Nguyen, Sally A. Penfold, Brooke E. Harcourt, Karly C. Sourris, Runa S. Lindblom, Mark Ziemann, David Steer, Assam El-Osta, Michael J. Davies, Leigh Donnellan, Permal Deo, Nicole J. Kellow, Mark E. Cooper, Trent M. Woodruff, Charles R. Mackay, Josephine M. Forbes, Melinda T. Coughlan: Processed foods drive intestinal barrier permeability and microvascular diseases, Science Advances. 7, 14, 15 p., eabe4841.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delineating a role for the mitochondrial permeability transition pore in diabetic kidney disease by targeting cyclophilin D</title>
      <link>/publication/2020_lindblom_ppif/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2020_lindblom_ppif/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Runa S.J. Lindblom, Gavin C. Higgins, Tuong-Vi Nguyen, Maryann Arnstein, Darren C. Henstridge, Cesare Granata, &lt;strong&gt;Matthew Snelson&lt;/strong&gt;, Vicki Thallas-Bonke, Mark E. Cooper, Josephine M. Forbes, Melinda T. Coughlan, Delineating a role for the mitochondrial permeability transition pore in diabetic kidney disease by targeting cyclophilin D, &lt;em&gt;Clinical Science&lt;/em&gt;, 134 (2): 239–259.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
