<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sih Min Tan on Matthew Snelson</title>
    <link>/authors/sih-min-tan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sih Min Tan on Matthew Snelson</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/authors/sih-min-tan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Processed foods drive intestinal barrier permeability and microvascular diseases</title>
      <link>/publication/2021_snelson_sciadvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2021_snelson_sciadvs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Snelson&lt;/strong&gt;, Sih Min Tan, Rachel E. Clarke, Cassandra de Pasquale, Vicki Thallas-Bonke, Tuong-Vi Nguyen, Sally A. Penfold, Brooke E. Harcourt, Karly C. Sourris, Runa S. Lindblom, Mark Ziemann, David Steer, Assam El-Osta, Michael J. Davies, Leigh Donnellan, Permal Deo, Nicole J. Kellow, Mark E. Cooper, Trent M. Woodruff, Charles R. Mackay, Josephine M. Forbes, Melinda T. Coughlan: Processed foods drive intestinal barrier permeability and microvascular diseases, Science Advances. 7, 14, 15 p., eabe4841.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long term high protein diet feeding alters the microbiome and increases intestinal permeability, systemic inflammation and kidney injury in mice</title>
      <link>/publication/2021_snelson_hpd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2021_snelson_hpd/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Snelson&lt;/strong&gt;, Rachel Elise Clarke, Tuong-Vi Nguyen, Sally Anne Penfold, Josephine Maree Forbes, Sih Min Tan, Melinda Therese Coughlan, Long term high protein diet feeding alters the microbiome and increases intestinal permeability, systemic inflammation and kidney injury in mice, Molecular Nutrition and Food Research 2021, 2000851&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the role of the metabolite-sensing receptor GPR109a in diabetic nephropathy</title>
      <link>/publication/2020_snelson_gpr109a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2020_snelson_gpr109a/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matthew Snelson&lt;/strong&gt;, Sih Min Tan, Gavin C Higgins, Runa SJ Lindblom, Melinda T Coughlan, Exploring the role of the metabolite-sensing receptor GPR109a in diabetic nephropathy,  Am J Physiol Renal Physiol, 318 (3), F835-F842&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complement C5a Induces Renal Injury in Diabetic Kidney Disease Via Disruption in Mitochondrial Metabolic Agility</title>
      <link>/publication/2019_tan_diabetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2019_tan_diabetes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;full-citation&#34;&gt;Full Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tan S, Ziemann M, Thallas-Bonke V, &lt;strong&gt;Snelson M&lt;/strong&gt;, Baker S, Jerums G, Skene A, Power D, MacIsaac R, Henstridge D, Wetsel R, Meikle P, El-Osta A, Forbes J, Cooper M, Ekinci E, Woodruff T, Coughlan M: Complement C5a Induces Renal Injury in Diabetic Kidney Disease Via Disruption in Mitochondrial Metabolic Agility &lt;em&gt;Diabetes&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 69, Issue 1, 2020, Pages 83-98&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
